## NEERAJ SHILWANT

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

An experienced engineer who is self-motivated, self-adept, and capable of utilizing technical skills for the benefit of the organization. My degree in engineering has enhanced my proficiency, and I look forward to working in an environment that promotes learning on a continual basis.

П	70570-3517
ы	70370-3317

meerajshilwant19@gmail.com



#### **EDUCATION**

# D.Y Patil College Of Engneering Akurdi, Pune

B.E - Artificial Intelligence and Data Science

**CGPA - 8.79** 2021 - 2024

Jai Hind Junior College,Pimpri

12th HSC Board **Percent - 83.38%** 2020

Jai Hind High School, Pimpri

10th HSC Board

**Percent - 85.40%** 2018

#### SKILLS

- React is
- C++ (basic DSA)
- DBMS: MySql
- Python
- Machine Learning
- Data Analytics
- Data Modeling Design
- Power Bi visualization
- Problem solving skills
- Positive attitude

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals.
- **Google** Data Analytics Coursera.
- Data Science in Python Coincent.
- Ethical Hacking Warrior.
- **Google Python** Automation Coursera.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## IT-IMPACT UNIQUE GATEWAY Pvt. Ltd

Software Developer INTERN

PUNE Aug 2022 - Feb 2024

- Leveraged **React.js**, **html**, **css** to develop responsive web applications for 18 Months.
- Integrated **machine learning models** into projects to enhance functionality and user experience.
- Resolved complex software issues for a diverse customer base, reducing average ticket resolution time by 40% and achieving a customer satisfaction rating of 95%.
- Managed and contributed to projects, focusing on seamless
  ML implementation within applications.
- Actively pursued continuous learning, staying updated with the latest web development trends and technologies.

## Personifwy

DATA SCIENCE INTERN

PUNE Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

- **Developed an Al-powered** chatbot that streamlines **the query resolution process** and provides a seamless user experience.
- Deploying a chatbot reduced response time and **increased customer retention** by 40%.
- Applying advanced statistical and machine learning techniques improves operational efficiency and strategic decision-making.
- The internship requires **programming skills such as Python**, Machine Learning Libraries Keras, Tensorflow.

#### **PROJECTS**

- <u>UserGit Analyzer React Js + ML</u>
- Business Providing Service Website (React JS)
- <u>Kasar Family Form link to GOOGLE spreadsheets</u> (Next Js)
- Age Prediction using Deep Learning (PyTorch and nltk) (upload the picture of any person and predict age).
- Al Chatbot (Chatbot for a hosting website).
- Stock Price Prediction Website using ML (Predict the Stock price based on moving Average).